Hi, this is Sean Hobson, and what we're talking about right now is how to become a good shooter off the move in a good fundamental way.
And one of the best fundamental ways we can do is the shot fake and drive.
Now, a shot fake is a very big tool to use against the defense, because everybody wants to block the shot.
So if I'm a defender, and I see him get the ball, and he's showing me a shot, the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to come jumping up here to block his shot every single time.
And that's going to get me off balance, it's going to get me out of the way I normally play, and so this guy's going to be able to drive around me almost every time.
So, what we're going to do is, we're going to have him shot fake.
Now when you shot fake it's very important not to move your feet.
You don't want to shot fake and take a step, and then take another step, or it's going to be a travel.
So, you want to catch the ball, shot fake, don't move your head, keep your eyes locked on the him.
You want to shot fake, and then cross the ball low, go past your defender.
You don't want to dribble to the side.
If he shot fakes, and dribbles to the side, then he's not going towards the basket.
His defender, all he has to do is just take a step and he's still in contact with him.
He wants to dribble towards the basket, and then make the shot.
So it's going to look like this.
Shot fake, dribble, and he makes the shot.
Good.
So, shot fake, dribble towards the basket, set yourself up for a good shot off the move, and then knock down the shot.
That's how you become a good shooter off the move.